Episode 8
에피소드 8
Young Master, even though you are a woman...
영스승님, 비록 여자이긴 하지만...
i know...
알아요...
Human life is only once.
인간의 삶은 한번뿐이다.
Even if there are bad intentions...
나쁜 의도가 있어도..
I will not risk my life.
나는 내 생명을 위험에 빠뜨리지 않을 것입니다.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
We had a therapist today.
오늘은 치료사를 모셨습니다.
Isn't that because you want to check...
확인하고 싶어서 그러는 거 아닌가 ...
Are my injuries real?
내 부상이 진짜인가요?
I know you are biased against me.
나는 당신이 나에 대해 편견을 가지고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
But Dr. Wu also said this.
하지만 우 의사도 이렇게 말했습니다.
That arrow could kill me.
그 화살은 나를 죽일 수도 있어요.
So I'm afraid of pain...
그래서 고통이 두렵다...
I use perfume to brighten it up.
나는 그것을 밝게하기 위해 향수를 사용합니다.
Do you still think I'm not afraid of death?
아직도 내가 죽음이 두렵지 않다고 생각하시나요 ?
At the ancestral rite...
조상제례식에서..
I don't know what I did...
내가 무슨 짓을 했는지 모르겠어...
Until you have doubts.
의심스러울 때까지요.
But more than anything, I'm worried about your safety.
하지만 무엇보다 씨의 안전이 걱정되는데요 ..
in my life.
내 인생에서.
Isn't that enough to prove my sincerity ?
내 진심을 증명하기에 충분하지 않은가 ?
I said something wrong.
제가 말을 잘못했어요.
Young master. ma'am.
젊은 주인님. 부인.
Your servant Mu Yao has arrived.
주인님의 종 무야오(Mu Yao)가 왔습니다.
Was that the player you beat last time?
저번에 당신이 구친 선수였나요?
Yes, Young Master. That's me.
응, 영 마스터. 그게 나야.
I heard that Master came to visit...
스승님이 방문하셨다고 들었는데 ...
So he asked me to invite you .
그래서 당신을 초대하라고 하더군요 .
rest well
잘 쉬다.
I won't bother you.
나는 당신을 귀찮게하지 않을 것입니다.
ma'am.
부인.
Madam, is your wound very painful?
마님 상처가 너무 아픈가요?
Your eyes are red.
당신의 눈은 빨간색입니다.
yes. It really hurts.
예. 정말 아파요.
Would you like to add some scent?
향기를 더해드릴까요?
no.
아니요.
Get rid of it from now on.
이제부터 없애세요.
Aren’t you afraid of getting sick, ma’am?
아플까 두렵지 않으세요, 부인?
As Dr. Woo said...
우 박사님 말씀대로...
If you overuse this sleeping perfume...
이 수면 향수를 과도하게 사용하면 ...
It will ruin your mind.
마음을 망칠 것입니다.
From now on, no matter how painful it is...
이제부터는 아무리 괴로워도...
I won't use it.
나는 그것을 사용하지 않을 것이다.
I can't lose my mind anymore.
나는 더 이상 정신을 잃을 수 없습니다.
Somehow...
어떻게든...
Some people can do it easily...
어떤 사람들은 쉽게 할 수 있습니다 ...
Earns the love and trust of others .
다른 사람들의 사랑과 신뢰를 얻습니다.
With just one look...
단 한번의 시선으로...
Other people will fall in love with them too.
다른 사람들도 그들과 사랑에 빠질 것입니다 .
As for other people...
다른 사람들은...
People who worked hard...
열심히 노력한 사람들..
I'm still receiving hostility and suspicion.
여전히 적대감 과 의심을 받고 있는데..
Despite trying hard...
열심히 노력했음에도 불구하고..
And it doesn't look any different than before.
그리고 이전과 다르게 보이지 않습니다 .
Madam, who are you talking about?
부인, 누구를 말씀하시는 겁니까?
ma'am.
부인.
The teacher said he was busy...
선생님은 바쁘다고 하더군요...
So I couldn't come.
그래서 나는 올 수 없었다.
Where are all the bodies?
모든 시체는 어디에 있습니까?
The hostess is confined to her bed...
여주인은 침대에만 갇혀있습니다...
And Master hasn't visited yet...
그리고 스승님은 아직 방문하지 않으셨습니다...
So the employees started to become lazy.
그래서 직원들이 게을러지기 시작했어요.
Madam, why don't you come inside...
부인, 안으로 들어가시는 건 어떨까요 ...
Then shall I sort it out?
그러면 내가 정리해줄까?
ma'am.
부인.
Your sister sent you some more jewelry.
당신의 여동생이 당신에게 보석을 더 보냈습니다.
Didn't I tell you to stop it?
내가 막으라고 하지 않았나 ?
My cupboard is almost full.
내 찬장은 거의 꽉 찼어요.
already.
이미.
But he didn't listen.
그러나 그는 듣지 않았습니다.
That person keeps sending me things...
그 사람이 계속 나한테 물건을 보내는데...
But I've never visited it.
하지만 한 번도 방문한 적이 없습니다.
He visited your mother this morning.
그는 오늘 아침에 당신의 어머니를 방문했습니다.
but...
하지만...
what?
무엇?
That's just...
그건 그저...
It's just that the master blocked it ...
단지 마스터가 막았을 뿐인데 ...
And that seems to tell them something...
그리고 그것은 그들에게 뭔가를 말하는 것 같습니다 ...
So they are afraid to come back.
그래서 그들은 다시 오기를 두려워합니다.
ma'am.
부인.
Are you going out?
외출 중이신가요?
I'm going to meet Jong Ye-ran.
종예란을 만나러 갑니다.
I need to talk to the teacher.
선생님이랑 얘기 좀 해야겠어요.
Please tell him I am here.
내가 여기 있다고 그에게 전해 주세요.
The teacher said...
선생님께서 말씀하셨어요...
He doesn't want to see you.
그 사람은 당신을 보고 싶어하지 않아요.
But there is something I really want to say to him .
그런데 그에게 꼭 하고 싶은 말이 있다 .
Mu Yao.
무 야오.
Like I said before...
내가 전에 말했듯이...
Now I don't have much choice...
지금 나는 많은 선택을 하지 않는다 ...
But I no longer...
하지만 나는 더 이상...
Having bad intentions towards you.
당신을 향해 나쁜 의도를 품고 있는 것.
I promise...
약속해요...
I will repay the debt I owe you little by little.
당신에게 진 빚을 조금씩 갚을게요 .
Can you trust me just once?
한번만 믿어줄래 ?
I am working ...
나는 일하고있다 ...
And I don't have time to meet anyone.
그리고 누구를 만날 시간도 없어요 .
Ah, Hua Chen...
아쿠, 화첸...
I'm here to ask for a divorce.
이혼을 요청하러 왔습니다.
What did I say...
내가 뭐라고 했는데...
This was done after careful consideration.
세심한 고려를 거쳐 진행되었습니다.
I hope the teacher takes this seriously.
선생님께서 진지하게 생각해주시길 바랍니다 .
I will go and wait for your answer.
나는 가서 당신의 대답을 기다릴 것입니다.
Two stupid women.
멍청한 여자 둘.
Everyone, why are you so sad?
여러분, 왜 그렇게 슬퍼하시나요?
I have my own plans.
나는 나만의 계획을 가지고 있습니다.
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
Do you think I'll be bullied?
내가 왕따를 당할 것 같아?
Kuiju, eat some snacks.
쿠이주야, 간식 좀 먹어라.
I didn't eat breakfast.
나는 아침을 먹지 않았습니다.
I can't even walk properly anymore .
이제는 제대로 걷지도 못해요 .
I think I'm too shameless again.
제가 또 너무 뻔뻔한 것 같아요.
Madam, are you okay?
부인 괜찮으세요?
Young man, you are promising.
젊은이여, 당신은 유망합니다.
You are a young man...
당신은 젊은 남자입니다 ...
The person who saved me...
나를 구해준 사람..
It's during ancestral rites, right ?
제사 때죠 ?
ma'am.
부인.
Yeah that's me
그래 그게 나야.
I couldn't hear you clearly at that time.
그 당시에 는 당신의 말을 명확하게 들을 수 없었습니다 .
What is your name?
이름이 뭐에요?
My Name...
내 이름...
Huarongzhou.
화룽저우.
How dare you look at your wife...
감히 부인을 쳐다보시다니...
Chenz!
첸즈!
You saved my life.
당신은 내 생명을 구했습니다.
I will remember your name.
나는 당신의 이름을 기억할 것입니다.
Coincidentally, our last names are the same.
공교롭게도 우리 성(姓)은 같다.
I think we were destined to meet.
내 생각엔 우리는 만날 운명이었던 것 같아.
How old are you?
몇 살이에요?
I am 16 years old.
나는 16 세입니다.
Then I am older than you.
그렇다면 나는 당신보다 나이가 많습니다.
I am one year older. Yes, I am 17 years old.
한 살 더 많아졌습니다. 네, 저는 17세입니다.
I will remember that you saved my life.
나는 당신이 내 생명을 구했다는 것을 기억할 것입니다.
fag.
열심히 일하다.
Thank you so much, ma'am.
정말 감사합니다, 부인.
Young Master, about the attack...
영 마스터님, 공격에 대해서...
I looked at it several times...
몇번이나 살펴봤는데 ..
And I noticed something suspicious.
그리고 수상한 점을 발견했습니다.
what?
무엇?
last year...
작년...
All traces of the Ge family have been erased...
게 가문의 흔적은 모두 지워졌다…
And they never showed up.
그리고 그들은 한 번도 나타나지 않았습니다 .
That didn't stop the investigation.
그렇다고 해서 조사가 중단되지는 않았습니다.
After all, people here still hate them...
결국 여기 사람들은 아직도 그들을 싫어해요...
Because they use fake, low-quality fragrances.
가짜 , 저품질 향료를 사용하기 때문에..
To harm people.
사람들에게 해를 끼치기 위해.
Once they know...
그들이 알고 나면...
They will report this to the authorities.
그들은 당국에 이를 보고할 것입니다.
It can be done...
그것은 할 수 있습니다 ...
If only there were a few of Ge's men...
Ge의 부하가 몇 명만 있었다면 ...
Who is hiding here?
여기 숨어있는 사람은 누구입니까?
But, there is no way...
하지만, 방법이 없습니다...
Suddenly a group of people will appear.
갑자기 한 무리의 사람들이 나타날 것입니다.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
I felt attacked...
공격을 느꼈다...
The goal is to steal our secret formula.
우리의 비밀 공식을 훔치는 것이 목표입니다 .
The crab family and the middle family...
게 가문과 중 가문...
That's how strong it is.
그만큼 강하다.
Besides that...
그 외에도...
Who else would dare attack?
또 누가 감히 공격하겠습니까?
The attacker...
공격자는 ...
Maybe he's from the Ge family.
어쩌면 Ge 가족 출신일 수도 있습니다.
Maybe there are people...
사람도 있을지도...
In our city...
우리 도시에서는...
It helps cover their tracks ...
그들의 흔적을 가리는 데 도움이 됩니다 ...
So many of them...
그래서 그 중 많은 사람들이...
You can stay here without being detected.
들키지 않고 여기에 머물 수 있습니다.
Or someone...
아니면 누군가...
On the other hand, please help them...
반면에 그들을 도와주세요 ...
So they can sneak into the city quickly.
그래서 그들은 빨리 도시로 몰래 들어갈 수 있습니다.
That means...
그 뜻은...
There are traitors hiding in the city...
도시에는 반역자들이 숨어있습니다 ...
Or was it the work of an outsider?
아니면 외부인의 작품이었나요?
Our guards will work harder to find...
우리 경비병들은 찾기 위해 더욱 노력할 것입니다...
And patrolling...
순찰도 하고...
To find the culprit.
범인을 찾으려면.
My Lord and Majesty can be sure of that.
나의 주님과 폐하께서는 그것을 확신하실 수 있습니다.
I'll talk about this with my mom ...
이 문제는 엄마한테 얘기해볼게 ...
But I suggest...
하지만 나는 제안한다...
Don't increase the guards...
경비병을 늘리지 마세요...
Except for the gates.
성문을 제외하고.
Make sure the intensity stays the same.
강도가 동일하게 유지되는지 확인하십시오.
How do I know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
What if we don’t increase the number of security guards?
경비원 수를 늘리지 않는다면?
The feast is about to begin.
향연이 곧 시작됩니다.
At this important moment...
이 중요한 시점에...
We can't lose face...
우리는 체면을 잃을 수 없습니다 ...
In front of merchants outside the city.
도시 외부의 상인들 앞에서.
In the end , there weren't many casualties...
결국 사상자는 많지 않았는데...
And now society is watching us.
그리고 이제 사회가 우리를 지켜보고 있습니다.
I wonder what I should do now...
이제 어떻게 해야 할 것 같은데 ...
To convince people...
사람들을 설득하기 위해서죠...
And be quiet and watchful...
그리고 조용히 경계하세요...
Instead of adding a controller...
컨트롤러를 추가하는 대신...
It can actually cause panic.
실제로 공황을 일으킬 수 있습니다.
But in the case of Mr. Ge's family...
그런데 Ge씨 일가의 경우는...
It's causing a lot of trouble...
말썽을 많이 일으키네요...
And many people have been harmed by their actions.
그리고 그들의 행동으로 인해 많은 사람들이 피해를 입었습니다.
Muda Muda is very attentive.
Muda Muda는 매우 세심합니다.
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
When I was busy just now...
지금 막 바빴을 때...
Chairman Lin left a message.
린 회장이 메시지를 남겼다.
What is it?
그게 뭐야?
Mrs. Hua wants a divorce.
Hua 부인은 이혼을 원합니다.
Are you divorced?
이혼했나요?
Teacher, it's meal time now.
선생님, 이제 식사 시간이에요.
Tuan?
투안?
I see you eat too little...
보니까 밥을 너무 적게 먹는데...
So I cooked this as a gift for you.
그래서 제가 당신을 위한 선물로 이걸 요리했어요.
I hope you enjoy it...
나는 당신이 그것을 즐기시기 바랍니다 ...
And you can understand the intention behind this gift.
그리고 이 선물 뒤에 숨은 의도를 이해할 수 있습니다 .
I think my teacher is the only person in my life.
나는 선생님이 내 인생의 유일한 사람이라고 생각합니다.
So anyway...
그래서 어쨌든...
I want to be too...
나도 되고싶다...
In his eyes, you are the only one.
그의 눈에는 유일한 사람입니다.
My love for him is very great...
그에 대한 나의 사랑은 매우 큽니다 ...
Until you understand...
이해가 될 때까지...
I will do anything to make him happy.
나는 그를 행복하게 만들기 위해 무엇이든 할 것입니다.
Ah, Hua Chen...
아쿠, 화첸...
I'm here to ask for a divorce.
이혼을 요청하러 왔습니다.
What I said...
내가 말한 것...
This was done after careful consideration.
세심한 고려를 거쳐 진행되었습니다.
I hope the teacher takes this seriously.
선생님께서 진지하게 생각해주시길 바랍니다 .
Your wife's hair is already dry.
부인의 머리는 이미 말랐어요.
Madam, you need to treat your wounds...
부인, 상처를 치료하셔야 합니다...
And sleep early.
그리고 일찍 자세요.
How old is Hua Rongzhou?
Hua Rongzhou는 얼마나 오래 되었습니까?
Do you work here?
여기서 일하시나요?
Almost a month.
거의 한 달.
Does your wife think there is something wrong with him?
부인은 그에게 뭔가 문제가 있다고 생각하시나요?
of.
의.
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
He is very handsome.
그는 매우 잘 생겼다.
We have a regular security guard at our house...
우리 집에는 단골 경비원이 있습니다 ...
With such a beautiful face...
이렇게 아름다운 얼굴로...
And the same last name as me.
그리고 나와 같은 성이요.
But I don't remember seeing it.
그러나 나는 그것을 본 기억이 없습니다 .
ma'am.
부인.
- I heard what you did... - Lee Hine.
- 당신의 행동을 들었어요... - 리 하인.
Is my father cheating on me?
우리 아버지가 바람을 피우고 계시나요?
What do you mean, madam?
무슨 말씀이세요, 부인?
Or maybe you have an illegitimate child...
아니면 사생아가 있거나...
Abandoned?
버려진 것?
Head Steward Hua was an honest man.
Hua 헤드 청지기는 정직한 사람이었습니다.
He cared only about business.
그는 오직 사업에만 관심을 가졌습니다.
He has never taken a concubine.
그는 첩을 취한 적도 없습니다 .
How could he do such a thing?
그가 어떻게 그런 일을 할 수 있었습니까?
Then what about my sister?
그럼 내 여동생은요?
ma'am.
부인.
How can you guess...
어떻게 추측할 수 있나요...
Is this like this about your family?
당신의 가족에 대해 이렇습니까?
Young Master is only 23 years old.
영 마스터의 나이는 고작 23세입니다.
He is still a child!
그는 아직 어린 아이입니다!
ma'am...
부인...
I think he's not in a good mood today .
오늘 그 사람 기분이 좋지 않은 것 같아요 .
It has to stop.
멈춰야 해.
ma'am.
부인.
Eat the soup while it is hot.
수프는 뜨거울 때 드세요.
I think it would be best for you to go to bed early, wife.
부인은 일찍 잠자리에 드는 것이 가장 좋을 것 같습니다.
Don't think much.
많이 생각하지 마십시오.
Please take good care of him.
그를 잘 돌봐주세요.
After all, he didn't look like an ordinary person.
결국 그는 평범한 사람처럼 보이지 않았습니다.
Madam, go to bed early.
부인, 일찍 자세요.
There are a lot of good-looking people around here .
여기 주변에는 잘생긴 사람이 많아요 .
Please take care of your health.
건강에 유의하시기 바랍니다.
Don't think too much about it.
그것에 대해 너무 많이 생각하지 마십시오.
correct.
옳은.
In the end, this situation...
결국 이 상황은...
It's different from the past.
과거와 다르다.
It wouldn't be strange if I met someone...
누군가를 만나도 이상하지 않을텐데 ...
This is someone I have never met .
한 번도 만난 적이 없는 사람입니다 .
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
It looks pretty valuable...
꽤 가치있어 보이는데...
But it looks very complicated.
하지만 매우 복잡해 보입니다.
Put it on your head...
머리에 쓰고..
This will make your throat sore and irritated.
그러면 목이 아프고 짜증이 날 것입니다.
I have to sell it tomorrow...
내일이라도 팔아야지...
And I saved money.
그리고 나는 돈을 저축했습니다.
There is more as far as I remember.
내가 기억하는 한 더 있습니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Packaged.
포장되었습니다.
Light a candle.
촛불을 켜십시오.
Teacher, why are you here?
선생님, 왜 여기 계시나요?
The servants did not say that the Lord was coming.
종들은 주님이 오신다고 말하지 않았습니다 .
Are you coming...
오시나요...
Would you like to get the answer to my question?
내 질문에 대한 답을 가져오시겠어요?
You thought I was going to kick you out, right?
내가 널 쫓아낼 거라 생각했지?
Until you start packing, right?
짐을 꾸리기 전까지는 그렇죠?
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
I can not sleep...
잠이 안 와요...
And I thought...
그리고 나는 생각했다 ...
I have never seen...
나는 본 적이 없다 ...
Jewelry sent by my sister...
언니가 보낸 보석..
So I got up to check it out.
그래서 나는 그것을 확인하기 위해 일어났습니다.
In that case...
그 경우에는...
Don't ever try to read my mind again.
다시는 내 마음을 읽으려고 하지 마세요.
The future?
미래에?
what?
무엇?
Are you in a hurry to leave?
서둘러 떠나시나요?
No, I just...
아니, 난 그냥...
Something has been confusing lately .
최근에 뭔가 혼란스러웠습니다.
Did you save me from the ancestral rite?
제사식에서 저를 구해주셨는지요 ...
Just to make up for your mistakes...
단지 당신의 실수를 만회하기 위해...
Then leave?
그럼 떠나?
Why do you say that, sir?
왜 그렇게 말씀하시나요 선생님?
My love for you is so sincere...
당신을 향한 내 사랑은 정말 진심이에요...
And no one has the right to judge me.
그리고 누구도 나를 판단할 권리가 없습니다.
But I overcame it...
그런데 극복했어요..
With my obsession.
내 집착으로.
Once my mind becomes clear...
일단 마음이 맑아지고...
I need to ask for a divorce from you...
이혼을 요청해야 당신과...
great. Because you love me so much...
좋아요. 당신이 나를 너무 사랑하기 때문에 ...
I will make your wish come true..
당신의 소원을 이루어 드리겠습니다..
And let you stay.
그리고 당신이 머물게 해주세요.
That's not a good idea.
그건 좋은 생각이 아니다.
I made a lot of mistakes.
나는 많은 실수를 저질렀습니다.
- I can't forgive... - Admitting mistakes is a good thing.
- 용서할 수 없어... - 실수를 인정하는 것은 좋은 일이다.
You almost died to save me...
당신은 나를 구하기 위해 거의 죽을 뻔했습니다 ...
And I am not an ungrateful person .
그리고 저는 배은망덕한 사람이 아닙니다 .
Besides, my house...
게다가 우리집..
You can support lazy people.
게으른 사람을 지원할 수 있습니다.
Sir, it is not what you think .
선생님, 당신이 생각하는 그런 것이 아닙니다 .
I can't...
난 할 수 없어...
Keeps you away.
당신을 멀리 유지합니다.
Your father is the deacon here.
네 아버지가 여기 집사야.
I too must protect his honor.
나 역시 그의 명예를 지켜야 한다.
If you're really sorry...
정말 미안하다면...
You can make up for your mistakes...
실수를 만회할 수 있다...
The future...
미래에...
Staying here...
여기 머물면서...
And live a peaceful life.
그리고 평화로운 삶을 살아보세요.
Sir, you are the authority here...
선생님, 당신이 이곳의 권위자입니다...
And my father is just a butler.
그리고 우리 아버지는 그냥 집사예요.
Tuan...
투안...
Tuan?
투안?
Teacher, you can go...
선생님, 가셔도 됩니다...
By the way, can you light a candle?
그런데 촛불을 켜줄 수 있나요?
I can't see anything.
나는 아무것도 볼 수 없습니다.
Sir, I'm not kidding.
선생님, 농담이 아닙니다.
I really can't see anything .
정말 아무것도 볼 수 없어요 .
Tuan?
투안?
Jong Ye-ran.
종예란.
You are ungrateful and inhumane.
당신은 배은망덕 하고 비인간적입니다.
Qianzhi didn't close the window?
Qianzhi가 창문을 닫지 않았습니까 ?
That's not important. I won't freeze.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 나는 얼지 않을 것이다.
If you close the window...
창문을 닫으면...
I think I'll probably bump into it a few more times.
아마 몇 번 더 부딪힐 것 같아요 .
Ji waiter.
지 웨이터.
This is your business.
이것은 당신의 사업입니다.
Don't leave it to me.
나에게 맡기지 마십시오.
Master told me to do so.
스승님이 그렇게 하라고 하셨습니다.
How dare I do something like that?
내가 어떻게 감히 그런 짓을 할 수 있지?
But I have to give it to you.
그러나 나는 그것을 당신에게 주어야합니다.
Or you have to do it yourself.
아니면 스스로 해야 합니다.
It's a hassle to go back and forth.
왔다 갔다 하기가 번거롭습니다.
That's not important. I don't care.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 나는 상관하지 않는다.
Hey, G!
헤이, 지!
Why are you so cruel?
왜 그렇게 잔인합니까?
You actually let go.
당신은 실제로 손을 놓았습니다.
Hey, didn't you always like me...?
야, 평소부터 좋아하지 않았어...?
Are you going to your wife's residence?
부인 거주지로 가시나요?
This is a great opportunity.
이것은 좋은 기회입니다.
You're the one. how?
너 뿐이야. 어떻게?
That's none of my business. I can't stand it.
그건 내 알 바가 아니야. 나는 그것을 참을 수 없다.
Hello, G.
안녕, 지.
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
The servants who work for that person...
그 사람을 위해 일하는 하인들은...
He always frowns when he sees me.
나를 보면 항상 눈살을 찌푸린다 .
If I go there again today...
오늘 또 거기 가면...
I'm afraid they will kick me out.
그들이 나를 쫓아낼까 두렵습니다.
As an honorable person...
명예로운 사람으로서...
And the guard commander...
그리고 수비대장..
How can you be so anxious ?
어떻게 그렇게 불안할 수 있나요 ?
When I see you. You're still young...
당신을 보면. 아직 어리시네요...
Also handsome.
또한 잘 생겼습니다.
Those servants will be happy...
그 하인들은 행복하겠지...
When I see you.
난 당신을 볼 때.
Hey, G!
헤이, 지!
ji!
지!
Why do you want to take it?
왜 가져가고 싶나요?
you told me
당신은 나에게 말했다.
so? We are at the lady's house.
그래서? 우리는 부인의 집에 있습니다.
He suffered serious injuries.
그는 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Let the Lord himself come.
주님께서 친히 오시게 하십시오.
Nona Chenz.
노나 첸즈.
If he does that...
그 사람이 그렇게 하면...
It would definitely be very awkward.
확실히 매우 어색할 것이다.
why?
왜?
There is no good reason in this world ...
이 세상에는 정당한 이유가 없습니다 ...
Why does the husband treat his wife so coldly?
남편은 왜 아내를 그렇게 차갑게 대하는 걸까요?
It really is.
정말 그렇습니다.
Is there a storm brewing early in the morning?
이른 아침에 폭풍이 불고 있나요?
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
ma'am.
부인.
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Nanfeng comes and says he will...
난펑이 와서 그러겠다고 하는데...
tell the truth
진실을 말하라.
They told me to get rid of it...
없애라고 하더군요...
Home cleanliness sign.
집 청결 표시.
Madam, you're still injured...
부인, 아직 부상을 입으셨네요...
But Master is not interested in your kindness .
하지만 스승님은 당신의 친절에는 관심이 없으십니다 .
Just give it to him.
그냥 그에게 주세요.
But you've just started taking on household chores...
그런데 이제 막 집안일을 떠맡기 시작하셨는데 ...
And I don't fully understand how you can do it ...
그리고 당신이 어떻게 할 수 있는지 완전히 이해하지 마십시오 ...
I studied...
공부했는데...
Do not occupy Zhong's residence.
Zhong의 거주지를 점유하지 마십시오 .
Because you already know the process of managing a house...
집을 관리하는 과정을 이미 알고 있으니까 ...
no difference...
차이 없음...
Whether I'm holding that sign or not.
내가 그 사인을 들고 있는지 아닌지.
Besides, I don't care about their money.
게다가 나는 그들의 돈에 관심이 없습니다 .
But ma'am, how could you...
그런데 부인, 어떻게 선생님이...
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
Zhong Yelan knows the truth about the temple...
Zhong Yelan은 사원에 대한 진실을 알고 있습니다 ...
And the plan I made to marry her .
그리고 내가 그녀와 결혼하기 위해 세운 계획 .
But the lady protected him from the arrows...
하지만 마님은 그를 화살로부터 지켜주셨는데...
And I almost died.
그리고 거의 죽을 뻔했습니다.
He couldn't be that cruel, could he?
그 사람은 그렇게 잔인할 수가 없지, 그렇지?
If anyone...
누군가 있다면...
Who tricked me into believing his lies...
누가 나를 속여 자신의 거짓말을 믿게 만들었는가...
All day...
하루 종일...
How should I treat him ?
그를 어떻게 대할 것인가 ?
Who dares deceive you, madam?
누가 감히 당신을 속이나요, 부인?
I will teach him a lesson.
나는 그에게 교훈을 가르칠 것이다.
Now in Jong Yeran's eyes...
이제 종예란의 눈에는...
I am that kind of person.
나는 그런 사람입니다.
So even though he was given arrows to protect him...
그래서 그를 보호하기 위해 화살을 받았음에도 불구하고...
That doesn't change the facts...
그게 사실을 바꿀 수는 없어요...
About what happened in the past.
과거에 있었던 일에 대해서 .
This is what I understand now.
이것이 내가 지금 이해하는 것입니다.
Please give Nan Feng an autograph.
난펑에게 사인을 주세요.
Okay, ma'am.
알겠습니다, 부인.
this.
이것.
Satisfied?
만족하는?
Teacher Qianzhi, please listen to me.
Qianzhi 선생님, 제 말을 들어주세요.
Quiet. No need to explain anything.
조용히 해. 아무것도 설명할 필요가 없습니다.
Don't come here again.
다시는 여기에 오지 마세요.
You are a jinx.
당신은 징크스입니다.
Every time I see you something bad happens.
당신을 볼 때마다 나쁜 일이 일어납니다 .
Nona Chenz...
노나 첸즈...
- Teacher Qianzhi... - Get out of here.
- Qianzhi 선생님... - 여기서 나가세요.
- Mr. Chenz. - Didn't you hear?
- 첸즈 씨. - 못 들었어?
He doesn't want to see you.
그 사람은 당신을 보고 싶어하지 않아요.
- Changan Gangukami - Nonachenji...
- 장안강구카미 - 노나첸지...
Unhappiness! You always bring bad luck!
불행! 당신은 항상 불운을 가져옵니다!
- Enyala! - Chenz...
- 엔얄라! - 첸즈...
go!
가다!
lose one's way!
길을 잃다!
How did this happen?
어쩌다가 이렇게 됐지?
My wife is talking about divorce...
부인이 이혼 얘기를 하는데...
In front of many servants and subordinates...
많은 하인 과 부하들 앞에서 ..
At the servant’s residence that day...
그날 종 거주지에서..
Now almost everyone knows.
이제 거의 모든 사람들이 알고 있습니다.
Qian didn't like it at first, but...
Qian은 처음에는 별로 좋아하지 않았지만..
That person is not someone...
그 사람은 누군가가 아니야...
Frustrating...
짜증나는...
And Yelan is not an irrational person .
그리고 옐란은 비합리적인 사람이 아니다 .
What's wrong with them?
그들에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Maybe he realized...
어쩌면 그는 깨달았을지도...
If you don't marry the person you want...
원하는 사람과 결혼하지 않는다면 ..
And the woman felt like she had married the wrong man...
그리고 그 여자는 자신 이 잘못된 남자와 결혼한 것 같은 기분이 들었습니다...
So there was a rift in both of them.
그래서 둘 다 균열이 생겼습니다.
they got married
그들은 결혼했다.
How could they take this matter lightly?
그들이 어떻게 이 문제를 가볍게 여길 수 있겠습니까?
Send someone there...
거기로 사람을 보내세요...
We invite Hua Qian tomorrow.
내일 Hua Qian을 초대합니다.
I want to ask...
묻고 싶다...
What happened between them?
그들 사이에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
great. majesty.
좋습니다. 전하.
wait.
기다리다.
These few days...
요 며칠...
He may still be recovering.
그는 아직 회복 중일 수도 있습니다.
Just wait 5 more days...
5일만 더 기다리세요...
Then send someone to invite him or her.
그런 다음 누군가를 보내 그를 초대하십시오.
good.
좋은.
Qianzhi?
Qianzhi?
Insing?
인싱?
Kuiju?
쿠이주?
Server Lee?
서버 리?
Where are all the bodies?
모든 시체는 어디에 있습니까?
Hello, madam.
안녕하세요, 부인.
Why are you the only bodyguard here?
왜 여기서 경호원은 당신뿐인가요?
Housing lacking people...
사람이 부족한 주택..
So I am the only one who takes care of this place.
그래서 이 곳을 돌보는 사람은 나뿐이야 .
What about my men?
내 부하들은 어쩌지?
The servants went to collect.
하인들이 수집하러 갔다..
You need it every day.
매일 필요합니다.
Are they all gone? What about the rest?
다들 없어졌나요? 나머지는 어떻습니까?
Housing lacking people...
사람이 부족한 주택..
So recently...
그래서 최근...
Some of your men...
당신의 부하들 중 몇몇은...
Sent elsewhere to help .
도움을 주기 위해 다른 곳으로 보냈습니다 .
There used to be no shortage of people.
예전에는 사람이 부족하지 않았습니다.
But after the relationship with Zhong Yeran broke down...
하지만 종예란과의 관계가 무너진 후...
Only then will there be deficiency.
그래야만 결핍이 있습니다.
great.
좋아요.
That means there's no need to...
즉, 그럴 필요가 없다는 뜻인데...
I remember many names now.
지금은 많은 이름을 기억하고 있습니다.
Because everyone went...
다들 갔으니까...
Why are you still here?
왜 아직도 여기에 있나요?
I am appointed to serve you...
나는 당신을 섬기도록 임명되었습니다 ...
So of course you are my priority.
그러니 당연히 당신이 나의 우선순위입니다.
I have to say this.
나는 이것을 말해야한다.
Teacher and I will never meet again...
선생님과 저는 다시 만나지 못할 거예요...
So there is no future here .
그러니 여기에는 미래가 없습니다 .
Find another job while you're still young.
아직 젊을 때 다른 직업을 찾아보세요 .
Madam, why are you outside?
부인, 왜 밖에 계시나요?
I didn't see anyone inside ...
안에는 아무도 못봤는데 ...
So I set out to find you.
그래서 나는 당신을 찾으러 나갔습니다.
I went to get your food.
나는 당신의 음식을 사러 갔다.
You can eat now.
이제 먹어도 됩니다.
Why should I take it?
왜 복용해야 하나요?
The chef used to bring it here.
셰프님이 여기로 가져오시곤 했어요.
I understand. Aren’t they short of people?
이해합니다. 그 사람들은 사람이 부족하지 않나요?
The chef ordered...
셰프님께서 주문해주신...
To reduce household expenses...
가계비를 줄이려면 ..
So that leaves us with this dish.
그래서 우리는 이 요리만 남았습니다.
That's not important. At least we still have two dishes left.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 적어도 우리에게는 아직 두 가지 요리가 남아 있습니다.
When I was living in exile...
내가 망명생활을 하던 시절..
Where have you been?
어디 있었어?
I went to buy you new clothes.
나는 네 새 옷을 사러 갔다.
Chief waiter Ji said.
지 수석 웨이터가 말했다.
Master, I ordered you to reduce your spending.
주인님, 지출을 줄이라고 명령하셨어요..
So you won't get a wife...
그러니까 부인은 안 받을 거예요...
Another new clothes.
또 새 옷.
That's not important. I have enough clothes...
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 내 옷은 충분해..
For my use.
내가 사용하기 위해.
ma'am.
부인.
What did you get?
무엇을 얻었나요?
Housekeepers are outrageous.
가정부들은 터무니 없습니다.
They say that Master ordered them to reduce their spending...
스승님이 지출을 줄이라고 명령하셨다고 하는데...
And they just gave me this cheap scent.
그리고 방금 나에게 이 값싼 향을 주었습니다.
That's not important. I will not use it from now on.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 이제부터는 사용 하지 않겠습니다 .
Anyway, I don't like it...
아무튼 싫다...
What they produce.
그들이 생산하는 것.
Next time, I will make it myself.
다음에는 제가 직접 만들어 보겠습니다 .
say. Master, I ordered you to reduce your spending.
말하다. 주인님, 지출을 줄이라고 명령하셨어요..
And what has shrunk now?
그리고 지금은 무엇이 줄어들었나요?
Please take a look at this.
이것을 봐주세요.
This is too much!
이건 너무해!
He even lowered the quality of the walnuts.
그는 심지어 호두의 품질도 낮추었습니다.
Walnuts are good for your brain.
호두는 뇌에 좋습니다.
How will he compensate me if I become stupid?
내가 멍청해지면 그 사람이 나한테 어떻게 보상해줄까 ?
ma'am...
부인...
Walnuts may look small, but they are edible.
호두는 작아 보이지만 먹을 수 있습니다.
- That's right, ma'am. - no!
- 그렇죠, 부인. - 아니요!
relax...
진정하다...
ma'am.
부인.
I can't argue with Tuan anymore .
더 이상 Tuan과 논쟁할 수 없습니다 .
After all, you still live in his house.
결국, 당신은 여전히 ​​그의 집에 살고 있습니다.
sit down.
앉아.
great.
좋아요.
He ordered spending to be reduced, right?
그는 지출을 줄이라고 명령했지요?
If so, I'll go out and buy mine.
그렇다면 나가서 내 것을 사겠습니다.
Besides, I have money.
게다가 나에겐 돈이 있다.
But madam...
그런데 부인...
You can't show yourself in public.
공개적으로 자신을 보여줄 수는 없습니다 .
correct.
옳은.
But it is possible.
그러나 가능합니다.
but...
하지만...
All major stores in Huangcheng...
Huangcheng의 모든 주요 매장 ...
Know who your servant is.
당신의 종이 누구인지 알아라.
If they...
만약 그들이...
Go out and shop every day.
매일 나가서 쇼핑하세요.
Adigan Bonus
애디건 보너스
my senior.
내 선배.
Young Master, why didn't you say you would visit?
젊은 스승님, 왜 방문하겠다고 말씀하지 않으셨습니까 ?
Mother is worried about Hua Chen’s injury.
어머니는 화첸의 부상을 걱정하고 계시는데..
So he asked to get a therapist to check it out.
그래서 그는 치료사를 데려와 확인해 달라고 요청했습니다.
difference.
상위.
I heard it from my sister-in-law's servant...
처제의 하인에게서 들었는데...
That's it for the past few days...
그게 요즘 며칠간...
You don't show interest...
당신은 관심을 보이지 않습니다 ...
Despite suffering serious injuries.
심각한 부상을 입었음에도 불구하고.
This is my family's business...
이건 내 가족의 일이야...
So you don't have to think about it.
따라서 그것에 대해 생각할 필요가 없습니다.
Yah...
야아...
great.
좋아요.